# NASIPHI GWIJA

PROFESSIONAL Information Technology professional with a BSc degree, specializing in systems development. Currently engaged in a full-stack software development internship at Uvu Africa. Certified facilitator, moderator, and assessor, demonstrating a commitment to continuous learning and a passion for technology-driven solutions. In 2021, I completed an internship and earned multiple Microsoft certificates, including CompTIA Cloud+, Service Desk Analysis, and Microsoft Administrator at Netcampus.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEV INTERN July 2023 - to date

**UVU Africa** Cape Town, South Africa

As a Full Stack Developer Intern, I've actively contributed to various projects showcasing my skills in web development and programming. I successfully created and launched my online portfolio, demonstrating proficiency in front-end technologies. Additionally, I collaborated on a group website with a chatbox implemented using Node.js, showcasing my back-end development skills. I also developed a banking app that features a password generator with a GUI using Python. My Python expertise extends to creating an Investment calculator. These projects not only reflect my technical capabilities but also highlight my commitment to innovative and functional solutions in the world of software development.

#### **CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE** 06/2022 to 09/2022

Vodacom, Cape Town, South Africa

- To monitor, track and coordinate all Technical department functions including tickets, calls, complaints and mail queries from customers.
- Ensure that customers are informed as to the progress of queries logged but not resolved.
- Ensure that the customers are called, and the resolution is confirmed before queries are closed.

### FACILATITION / TRAINING 06/2020 to 12/2023

Usapho Loluhle, East London

- Planning and creating the lesson plan
- Task management, motivating learners and managing the emotional culture of the group
- Monitoring and assessing portfolios.

## **STUDENT** 02/2021 to 02/2022

**Netcampus**, Cape Town, Soth Africa

- Life or soft skills
- End User Training
- Microsoft Teams MS 100
- Microsoft 365 Fundamentals MS 900
- Windows 10 MD 100
- Modern desktop Technician MD 101
- Service Desk Analysis SDA
- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals AZ 900
- Microsoft Administrator AZ 104

# CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- C#
- C++
- Java Script
- HTML
- PhP
- Life/Soft Skills
- Python

- End User Training
- Microsoft Teams MS 700
- Microsoft 365
  Fundamentals
- MS 900
- Windows 10 MD 100
- Modern Desktop

- Technician MD 101
- SDA Service Desk Analyst
- Microsoft Azure
- Fundamentals AZ 900
- Administrator AZ 104

#### **EDUCATION**

Nozuko Senior Secondary School Grade 12, Physical Science, Life

Science, Mathematics, Geography, 2012

Richfield Institute of Technology, Durban

**BSc IT: BSc**, IT, 2017

Modules: Artificial Intelligence 700, Computer Security700, IT Project Management 731, Programming 731, Programming 741, Software Engineering Management 700, Data Warehousing & Data Mining Modules: IT Group Project 732, Programming 732, Programming 742 Research Methodology 800, Work Integrated Learning 700